♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can
find, la la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor
his mind, la la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end, la la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science
facts, la la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
- I like the way you melted
the bumpers for effect.
- Oh, well, what's
that there then?
- Well, that's a 440 with twin
four-barrels and cherry bombs
hopped up with hooker headers,
thresh pipes, glass packs,
delivering 600 horsepower
with 1300 full pounds
of torque in the axle.
- Lays rubber in every gear.
- I glued it!
- Yeah.
- Oh, well, that's great, Gypsy.
That's really great.
- [Magic Voice] Commercial
sign in 15 seconds,
and I mean it this time.
- Oh, well, don't
say hi, jeepers.
- Gee.
- Well, it's great that
you guys have a hobby.
- Yeah, we were sort of
tracing the development
of the American muscle car
and its symbiotic relationship
to the feelings of isolation
and disillusionment
of postwar adolescents.
You know, the almost
mythic leather-clad loner
in the hot rod with the secret
and the soul in torment.
You know, his spirit
lives on, Joel,
finding its deepest meaning
in the songs of Morrisey
and Bruce Springsteen,
the Turtles.
- Yeah, I mean, if not for
the limitations of space,
we ourselves might be riding
through the mansions of glory
in our suicide machines,
jammed together on the highway
with broken heroes on a
last chance power drag.
- Yay. Woo.
- Well, I guess we would then.
- Wrap your hands
'cross my velvet rims,
and strap your hands
'cross my engines.
- All right, who
taught her that?
Which one of you?
- [Magic Voice] Commercial
sign in five, four,
three, two, commercial sign now.
(upbeat music)
- Now, look, Gypsy.
You don't have velvet
rims, all right?
And I don't want anybody
strapping anyone's hands
across anyone's
engines, okay, capiche?
- Okay.
- Evil hell-spawn are
calling, so behave.
- Come in, Joel, my
little space guy,
my little man who's
trapped up there,
my little person who we
control in a funny kind of way.
- Why don't you hit
the sack, Frank?
I'll take over from here, okay?
- Thanks, Dad.
- Well, Joel, we're
gonna swing right into
this week's invention exchange.
Frank?
- You know, when you've
been hospitalized
as frequently as I have,
the same old hospital food
gets to be a real drag,
particularly the
flavorless swill
that they pump
intravenously into your arms
as you drift in and
out of consciousness.
- That's why I've
invented these new, tasty,
boil in the bag
intravenous dinners.
- Who says a coma
can't be delicious?
- That's right.
No more glycopyrrolate
administered drably
at .8 milligrams per
liter of Ringer's Lactate.
This is hardy Irish
stew with cubed lamb.
- Mmm.
- And this is a delightful
poulet au vin rouge
that we have here.
- Mm. Is that thyme I'm tasting?
- 60 parts per million, Frank.
Here's cauliflower,
and would you like to
see our dessert cart?
- (chuckling) Should I?
- Well, we have Calimyrna
figs in a port sauce
that's very tasty, or almond
cake with apricot coulis.
It's really decadent.
- Okay.
You talked me into it.
But please, small portions.
- What do you think, Joel?
- I don't.
- Whoa. Good one.
- Deep.
Yeah.
- Anyway, thanks.
Our invention exchange
this week, sirs,
are based on the old
classic pop-up books
we had when we were kids.
But now that I've grown
up, my tastes have changed,
and I like a more
sophisticated fare.
So we all got together and
came up with some pop-up books
for some adult titles like
Charles Dickens'
"Great Expectations".
- Oh, look at that.
Isn't that sweet?
- Birthday cake with rats on it.
- Oh, there's the
pop-up version of
Tolstoy's "Anna Karenininina".
- Oh, this is one
of my favorites.
Woo-woo!
- That's the end of the book.
- And for that touch of despair,
there's always Albert
Camus' classic,"The Plague".
- Ahh.
That's how that goes.
- And I made a special
one, a pop-up version
of William Burroughs'
"Naked Lunch".
- No. Why?
- No. Why? Why?
I don't think we should.
That wouldn't be right, sirs.
- Ah, Joel, I was just
fluffing Frank's pillow.
Well, your, your movie
today is, is really bad.
Uh, it's called "Master
Ninja I", I think.
Enjoy!
Push the button, Frank.
- I had Jell-O today.
- Oh, right. I'll get it.
(Klaxon blaring)
- Whoa! We got movie sign!
No, they were just
having a pillow fight.
- Gee, those guys are mean.
- "Master Ninja I"?
A wandering ninja I.
All right, Lee.
- [Joel] Hey, lookit.
He's black and blue
from all that fighting.
- Bluer than I remember.
- [Tom] You see,
he learned too late
that man is a feeling creature.
- [Joel] Okay, Elvis,
we know you're in there.
- What, did Lee Harvey
Oswald shoot this footage?
- [Tom] Hey, Sho Kosugi!
Is that the kind of
thing you have with rice
and, uh, little nori wrappers?
It's a food, Chinese food.
- [Max] Hi.
I'm Max Keller.
- [Joel] I'm a seagull.
- [Max] This is how I
usually leave a bar.
- [Tom] Mm-Axe.
- [All] Max.
- [Max] A bunch of bikers
were harassing a young couple.
Naturally, I had
to try to stop 'em.
I don't think they liked me.
- [Joel] Demi Moore.
- [Tom] Without a Clu Gulager.
- [Max] Stick around.
This should be fun.
- Not with Claude Akins in it.
- [Tom] Oh, look.
Now he's the great Karl
Michael Demer. Ooh.
- [Joel] Thank you, Robert
Clouse, for I don't know what.
- Hey, uh, you want
to check the oil
while you're under there?
And while you're at
it, check your career.
- Get out of there!
- No, no!
Please don't hurt us.
(crowd shouting)
- [Joel] Thank you. It
was a lovely wedding.
(horn honking)
(tires squealing)
- Who was that?
- Hey, that's Max Keller!
- [Tom] Huh?
How did they know him?
- Oh, we're in
Deadwood, South Dakota.
- [Tom] Oh.
Uh-oh, whoa!
- Sidehackin.
- Woo.
(all groaning)
- [Tom] Oh, the carnage.
Back to you, Ed.
That kills me.
- [Max] Halfway across
the world was a man
who was going to change my life.
John Peter McAllister, the
only occidental American
ever to become--
- Miss Japan.
- A ninja.
- [John] Time for you
to go, little fella.
- [Tom] I tawt I taw a
gwade B actor. I did, I did!
It's Wee Van Cweef!
- [Joel] It's eight at night.
You can take off your jammies.
- [Tom] He dresses
like Sheila E.
- [Joel] I do like the John
Cage soundtrack though.
- [Tom] There's the John
Cage right there. (chuckling)
- Aw, cripes.
It's those Turtles.
They moved next door.
And now I'll never
get any sleep.
- [Joel] Boy, is
this ever Japan.
You know, you can really
tell this is Japan.
- Mm-hm.
- Ooh, that stings.
Ouch.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Benihana, no!
- [Tom] Hey, batter.
Hey, batter, batter.
Hey, batter.
Swing!
- Okay.
The couch will be first base,
and invisible guy on third.
- [Tom] Oh, my
knee. Oh, my elbow.
Oh, oh, my thigh.
Oh, oh, my back. Oh, my throat.
Oh, oh, oh, my shin.
Oh, my shoulder.
- [Joel] Tonight on Bravo,
Martha Graham's
new dance company.
- Oop, they're gonna need
a new roll of tissue.
- [Tom and Joel] Mm-hm.
- [Joel] So I called
Allstate immediately.
- [Tom] Lee Van Cleef
is Master Ninja.
(Joel groaning)
- Meanwhile, in the movie 1941--
- [Max] He's on his way
to the United States
to find the daughter
he never knew he had.
- [Tom] Yes.
- [John] Ellerston.
- [Joel] Ellerston?
Weird name for a daughter.
- [Max] Once he got out alive.
- Look, I'm getting
on that plane,
and where I'm going
I can't be with me.
(tires squealing)
- [Tom] Wait, sir.
You forgot your credit card.
- Oh. Those IUDs are dangerous.
- [Tom] Boy, aren't they?
- [Joel] Now, wait a minute.
Is it me, or did
I just lose face?
- Meanwhile, in Illinois, U.S.A.
(all chuckling)
♪ Gave a girl a
ride in my wagon ♪
I love that song.
- Someone in the Twilight Zone.
- [Tom] Look, he's
talking to the sound man
lying on the floor.
- Wait! Wait!
- Demi Moore?
I've dreamed of her
running out of the woods
into my Chevy van!
- Whoa!
- [Tom] Whoa, that's Demi Moore!
Whoa!
- Help me, please.
Don't wait, please.
- I wasn't even gonna stop.
- Whoa. You're a mess.
Were you at Prince's house?
- [Joel] Special guest
appearance by the car
from "Stranded in
Space", the Fury III.
- And what a Fury it is.
- Don't do that. I
like classical music.
- Good. Henry likes Mozart.
He saw "Amadeus" through
my pocket three times.
- Henry?
- That little guy there with
the brown fur and Fonda eyes.
- Henry, Portrait
of a Serial Gerbil.
(car horn honking)
- Who's this behind us?
- [Joel] Must have got separated
from the wedding party.
- Just get me out of here, okay?
- Hey, Where do you get those
dash-mounted gerbil cages?
- What does it look like?
Please, just take
me to the airport.
- You really must wanna
get away from this guy.
- No, no.
My father's airport,
Trumbull's Airfield.
It's right on the other
side of the trees.
You've gotta know where that is.
- Just passing through.
- [Tom] Geez, doesn't
your dad have an airport?
- Do you know that
guy behind us?
- Yeah, I know him.
- Husband or boyfriend?
- No, he's a horn salesman.
- I don't have
either. Look, mister?
- Max Keller.
- Holly Trumbull.
You're great, and
I'm really scared.
And all I ask is just
please take me to my home.
- Okay, okay. I'll take
you, I'll take you.
- [Tom] Do you need a
lozenge or something?
- [Joel] Filmed in
Mendecino County, Illinois.
- Sorry you got into this.
- Six more of those little
suckers going like hell.
- You bastard!
(lively synth music)
♪ Ain't got no rearview mirror ♪
(siren blaring)
- [Joel] You know, you're kind
of a high-maintenance day,
you know that?
- Left out of this
damsel in distress story.
Like, that's a cop behind us?
- Just don't stop.
- [Joel] Oh wow.
- Listen, lady.
Cops and I don't
quite snuggle up.
- Sheriff Kyle has
a personal vendetta
against myself and my father.
- Vendetta?
- Take a better look, okay?
Do I need to spell
it out for you?
The man tried to rape me.
- The cop?
(gun firing)
- [Tom] Now he's
trying to shoot me.
S-h-o-o-t.
- How do I get myself
into these things?
- Pull over.
This is the sheriff's office.
- Office?
That's a car.
- Brace yourself
against the dash,
and don't let Henry fall out.
He gets crazy when he's mad.
♪ Here comes your TV car chase ♪
♪ It's the TV car chase theme ♪
♪ Your TV car chase ♪
♪ Your TV car chase theme ♪
Hah!
Boogie!
♪ TV car chase ♪
Whoa.
(all cheering)
- I love that.
- I hope Steven J.
Cannell was in that car.
- Don't pass go, Max.
Go directly to jail, Max.
- Do not collect $200.
- [Tom] Only you can
prevent car explosions.
- [Man] I thought
you died on me.
You haven't moved for an hour.
- A warrior in
16th century Japan
sat under an icy waterfall.
- [Joel] He looks like
one of Henson's rats.
- Like this, without
moving, for 86 hours.
- Why'd he do that?
- I can't imagine.
- Look, I'm going for the tree
if you keep talking, old man.
- Slow heartbeat.
- [Tom] Seems I've
been drinking a lot.
- Open the door of the senses.
Listen to the silence.
- Mind if we don't talk
for the rest of the trip?
- You must be a lot
of laughs at a party.
- Do you think you,
um, could stick around?
I might need you.
- I'm going off-duty
for the day.
- Oh, sure. A loner, I got it.
Sit reading the classified
ads in a local motel
until Dick Powell comes running
down the television alley
at midnight with
a gun in one hand.
- Ah, let Dennis Miller
do Dennis Miller, Demi.
- Is my tummy bulging?
- [Tom] Hey, how's
Bruce these days?
- Um, he had his hands on me.
Sorry.
- That makes three of us.
Henry was just
getting to like you.
So where's a good place
to stay around here?
- Shallow grave.
Train tracks are nice.
- Clover Leaf Motel is back
down the road a couple of miles.
- Clover Leaf?
Maybe that'll change my luck.
So long.
- Max, um, I believe you
can order chilled champagne
even after midnight,
in case Dick Powell's
company isn't enough.
- Won't be.
- What are they talking about?
- [Tom] I have no idea.
(Henry squeaking)
- Don't worry.
I'm not gonna leave this
bar through the window, pal.
After wrecking
the sheriff's car,
I thought I'd take a break.
I didn't know McAllister
was right behind me.
- [Tom] Allister McAllister?
- [Max] You ever meet
a ninja in a bar?
It's a lot of fun.
- He looks about as much
like a ninja as Irene Ryan.
Heck, it is Irene Ryan.
(soft exotic music)
- [Joel] You know, everybody's
gonna know he's a ninja
if they play that theme every
time he comes in somewhere.
- Oh, everybody's got
their own theme music.
- [Tom] Hey, what's
a guy gotta do
to get beat up in this place?
- Hey, Max.
Max, over here.
(upbeat country music)
- [Joel] Hm, that's funny.
They've quit playing
my theme music.
- [Tom] Isn't that the guy
from "Blazing Saddles"?
- I wanted to buy
you a drink, partner,
for bringing Holly
back in one piece.
Last time he blacked her eye.
Someday, someone's gonna
settle it with the sheriff.
- By the way, who are you?
- I'd like to do it myself.
- What'll it be?
- At one time, a Singapore Sling
would've been the only answer.
- [Tom] Now I want
Peanut Buster Parfait.
- I'm looking for this person.
- I sell drinks.
- [Joel] Do you take
"Happenings" coupons?
- Do you want information?
There's the sheriff right there.
- [Joel] It's "Over the Top"!
- Hi, uh, could I talk
to you for a second?
- No!
- That's enough, boys.
- Oh, well. Lookit here.
- [Tom] Yeah, size 8 petite.
A little airport negligee, eh?
- You know how to strut
this down the stem, old man?
Hm? (chuckling)
- [Joel] I'll just die if
they find my Tiger Balm.
- Tres bonita, darling.
- You may not touch that.
- Just keeps gettin'
better, don't it?
- I've been hearing about
him down at the truck stop.
- [Joel] It's a
ninja truck stop.
- That old man can
take care of himself.
- Yeah, well, the sheriff
and I have a prior.
- Go for it, kid.
Hard and fast.
(upbeat music)
(Max shouting)
- [Tom] Out you pixies go!
Liar! You liar, you!
- That's enough!
That's enough!
Let's get that loudmouth.
- [Tom] Which one?
(all cheering)
- [Joel] Hey, must be
a health inspector.
Tilt.
- Hey, look, if you
lost your quarter,
just fill out a form and, oh.
- [Tom] What do we do
with these here tokens?
Good thing I'm not
a cigarette machine.
This guy woulda kicked
my butt. (chuckling)
- 8 ball, corner, well,
you know the rest.
- [Joel] Hey, uh,
it unscrews. Aw.
- [Tom] This rules.
- [Joel] Oh, it started
falling before he kicked it.
- Hey, was that necessary?
Look, Lee.
We made some mistakes.
You made some mistakes.
- I need your help.
- [Joel] Hey, I got
some tools in my truck.
- Ever think of hiring
out as a tornado?
- Just get me outta here.
- [Joel] Man, is he hammy.
- [Tom] Hey, it smells like
urine and cedar chips in here.
- Let's beat cheeks.
Little tiny ones.
(suspenseful music)
- Crazy.
- [Tom] Dun-dun-dun dun-dun dun.
- Do you always carry an arsenal
with you everywhere you go?
- You always carry a hamster?
- All my possessions
are with me.
Some are more
lethal than others.
- I was in a bar
one time in Saigon.
- [Tom] Yeah, right.
When you were a baby.
- This young dude comes and
tears the place to pieces,
like it was made outta nothing.
- I'll get out right here.
- Said he was a ninja.
- A ninja?
- Yeah, he carried a variety
of different little weapons
in a leather pouch.
- Oh, that's a chiropodist.
- [Joel] Hm?
- Hey, what else you got
in that suitcase of yours?
- My toothbrush.
- [Joel] Which could
rip a man's teeth out.
- How could you be hurt?
I mean, no one
even came near you.
- Shuriken wound.
It's a small spiked wheel
in the small of my back.
Keeps reopening.
- We better stay out
of the emergency rooms
till the sheriff gets
tired of watching 'em.
- [Tom] Yeah, and you'd better
take the wheel out of your back.
- Find someplace else.
- You little dickens.
- Your home?
- You're traveling in it, Jack.
- [Tom] You're jacking
in it, Traveler.
- Mr. Trumbull, any one
of my client's proposals
would make you a
very wealthy man.
- It's Claude Akins, and
he's got his ape mask!
Oh no. It's just Claude.
- Buy yourself LaGuardia.
- Eh. Coach would be cheaper.
- In my office there's
a picture of a field
with a jenny sitting in it.
- [Tom] That's that
Wyeth painting.
- A man in a leather flying
jacket wearing a red scarf.
He's got his arm around the
shoulder of another man.
- [Joel] Oh, Tom Selleck.
- You know where that
field is, Mr. Havilland?
- You've caused my client
to lose a lot of money.
- A William Daniels wannabe.
- Unnecessary grief.
- That field's right here,
and the man in the
leather flying jacket
wearing a red scarf,
that's my father.
- Oh, it was a trick question.
- The older man with the biplane
was a fellow named
Wilbur Wright,
who'd gone to have
lunch with my father
because he'd invented
a little thing called
a turn and bank indicator.
Now, Mr. Wright
thought that this
should be a good place
to build an airport.
- Bad place to film a movie.
- And my father thought so too.
- I can assure you that--
- [Tom] I have no clue
what you're talking about.
- If Mr. Christensen
would like to come by here
and take a plane ride,
it's on the house.
- [Joel] Oh, he's gonna
stab him in the throat
like "Godfather III".
- Maybe he'd have a
better perspective
of the world from 5000 feet.
- Those lenses cost
me a lot of money.
Please, be very careful--
- Oh. I thought he was
gonna rip off his mustache.
- Every time I fly
into this airport
I look down through the clouds.
- [Tom] And I spit.
- And I see some good memories.
They wouldn't look that
good any place else.
And you tell Mr.
Christensen that.
- [Joel] Mr. Christensen,
hoist the main sail!
- Very well.
- Ooh! With the oh, thank
you very much, Mr. Doyle.
- [Tom] Claude Akins, ladies
and gentlemen, Claude Akins.
Let's give him a big hand.
He'll be back later in the show.
- [Joel] You know,
say what you want,
but Claude Akins
has a nice rump.
- [Tom] Boy, don't he though?
- You guys talking
about my butt?
- D'oh!
- Yeah, you crack me up.
I've seen the show.
- Thought you might
need some help.
There's a run on old guys
getting tough tonight.
- What're you doing back here?
- Who's Christensen?
- Property owner.
Owns as much of this town
as the law will allow.
- Ah, the character
meeting place.
- Shopping center.
- Just stay out of this, Holly.
- Got into some more
trouble, and brought it back.
Some old guy the
sheriff was hassling.
- All the way from town, huh?
(siren blaring)
- [Tom] Someone's
broken ape law.
- My van.
- Take him to the PQ.
- Get him a Dilly Bar.
- [Joel] Mr. Akins, deputy
wanted to see your butt.
- [Kyle] Start
searching over there.
- You got a warrant, sheriff?
- [Tom] Yeah, got a
made-for-TV warrant right here.
- Because you better have one
before you take one more step
onto my tarmac, and a
stretcher to take you off.
- Threatening an officer of
the law is a serious offense.
- You're not listening to me!
Now you get off my property!
- [Joel] Man's gotta know
his limitations, Clint.
- [Kyle] All I'm gonna need
is one more FAA entrenchment,
and I'll be back
to shut you down.
Chew on that.
- What happened?
Kyle?
- Who's Kyle?
- He's hurt.
- [Holly] Who is he?
- I'd like to know the
answer to that one myself.
- [Tom] He's the Ugly.
- [Joel] No, he's the Bad.
- [Tom] Oh.
- See you later?
- [Tom] Ooh.
Lotta electricity in
that, I'll tell you.
- Wow. He got paid
to kiss Demi Moore.
- [Tom] Most people have.
Ooh.
- Did she kiss you?
- This guy.
- Seemed like the right moment.
- [Tom] D'oh!
- Guess they're just
not making ninjas
the way they used to, huh.
- Guess not.
- What a burn.
- What do you know of the ninja?
- Well, my uncle in Milawukee's
best friend is a ninja.
- You know, I'm surprised
your fellow ninjas let you go.
- There was a send-off.
- Yeah, pinwheel in the back.
Nice.
Max Keller.
Do I get to call you Master?
- It's got a ring to it.
- [Tom] Yeah, so does a bathtub.
- John Peter McAllister is
the name on the discharge.
- From where?
They don't teach what you
did in any army I know of.
- Army Air Corps.
At the end of the war I
found myself in Japan,
a ticket home,
and nowhere to go.
- Why didn't you go home?
- Something about
the tranquility.
- [Joel] The tranquility
of postwar Japan?
(Tom chuckling)
- What brought you home?
Or were you just running?
- You know, this scene is
really faithful to the book.
- [Tom] It shows.
- My daughter.
One I didn't even know I had.
- [Tom] Her name's Lefty.
Wrote to me a month
ago from Ellerston.
- This picture's taken outside
of one of Trumbull's hangars.
- [Joel] Uh, why's she
handcuffed to a biplane?
- And that's why you've traveled
halfway around the world
after 30 years?
Just to find her?
- What other reason
could there be?
- [Tom] World perks card,
frequent flyer miles.
- You're looking over
your shoulder for someone.
Secrets locked inside your head
that no one else can know about?
- Lots of secrets.
- I'll take the
ones you can give.
(chair scraping)
- [Tom] Ah!
- Sounded like his
stitches were ripping.
[Tom] Oof.
- I don't understand.
- I'm making a deal with you.
I'll help you find your daughter
if you'll teach me what
you did in that bar.
I mean, the way you
moved, the way you felt!
- [Tom] The way
you sang off-key!
- There's all kinds of tricks
in that suitcase of yours.
- You would not
endure the discipline.
- [Max] Try me!
- Or the emotional commitment.
- What, what, you don't
think I got emotions?
- Too many of them.
- [Joel] You're
practically Leo Buscaglia.
- Take on six attackers at once.
That's not where it is, Max.
- I can hack it.
- You've got nice qualities.
- [Joel] Strong cheekbones.
- But not for a ninja.
Anyway I'm a
cantankerous old man,
who's lived alone
a lot of years.
- [Tom] And I'm gonna learn
the true meaning of Christmas.
- I can see why.
I've been alone too.
- [Tom] Aww.
- Just thought I'd
try another route.
- [Joel] Another paper route.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- Anyway, hang in
there, old fella.
- I'll hang in.
- Good luck finding
your daughter.
- Go to bed, old man!
- [Tom] This dialogue was
lifted from "Then Came Bronson".
Don't you think?
- Say hi to Dick.
- Good luck finding yourself.
- What? Did you say something?
- [Tom] When
Mummenschanz goes bad.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Uh, no.
It goes in, in the tank.
No.
- That's enough.
Get to the hangar.
- Cold, cold.
You're nowhere near the tank.
Warmer.
- [Tom] Here's Katherine
Hepburn gassing up her plane.
(melancholy music)
(Henry squeaking)
(Tom gasping)
- Guess nobody wants us, Henry.
- [Joel] This is the
dark night of our souls.
(engine starting)
(suspenseful music)
- Ow, ow, ow, ow,
ow, ow, ow, ow.
- [Holly] Bye, Max.
- [Tom] Ooh.
Flames.
- [Joel] Is that
Mrs. O'Leary's barn?
- Looks like Edie Sedgwick
fell asleep again.
- [Tom] Oh, and speaking of
flaming, it's about time to go.
- I've got things to do.
- Did you know that actresses-
- Where's Crow going?
- You know, actresses always
run into a flaming building.
Hey, Crow, come back!
Hey.
Hey, little circuit guy.
What are you working on?
You kind of left the theater
in a hurry, you know.
- Yeah, what's the
hoodoo, skitter?
- Hey, uh, dim the lights, guys.
I got something to show you.
Uh, Cambot, play some of that
appropriately tension-filled
incidental music.
- What's this all about?
- We can't talk here.
- Crow, aren't you being
just a bit overdramatic?
- Well, sure.
But I've stumbled upon
a plot that once exposed
will blow the lid off the
entertainment industry.
Did either of you two stop
to consider for a moment
why Timothy Van Patten
is in this stupid film?
- Uh, Patrick Swayze was busy?
- Good guess, but
I thought of that.
No, we're dealing with
something even more terrifying
than the Swayze conundrum.
I'm talking about a
plot more insidious.
Gentlemen, I present
for your consideration,
assist, the Van Patten Project!
Sitting stop the Van
Patten corporate structure,
Dick Van Patten,
or should I say,
Don Dick Van Vito
Patten Corleone!
His evil plan, to place
an annoyingly bad actor,
preferably one of his own
hellish drop, in every B grade,
made-for-TV and low-budget
film in Hollywood.
- Uh, that would be
all of them. (laughing)
- (clearing throat) His
plan is quite simple.
He begins his career
with the Lunts,
gadding about in
legitimate theater.
Then he snatches a plum role
in the television sitcom "Mama".
The popular show runs until '56,
then, mysteriously, no Dick.
Fade to the '70s,
decade of shame,
Dick explodes across the
television screen with shows
like "The New Dick Van Dyke
Show" and "The Partners",
"When Things Were Rotten",
and "Eight Is Enough",
a show that launched
the criminal career
of many a young hack talent.
- [Joel] Uh-huh.
- Now, Timothy Van
Patten comes forth
to do his evil in "The
White Shadow", "The Master".
Then James Van Patten
gets a small role
in the short-lived
western, "The Chisholms".
And then what happens to him?
I don't know!
And then there's
Vincent, Vincent,
who is truly abysmal
in "Apple's Way"
and "Three for the Road",
then became the Bionic Boy.
At least he could
smell the bacon frying
and had the good sense to
become a tennis player!
The parallels with "The
Godfather" are inescapable.
- Sad when it happens to
somebody you know, isn't it?
- I know.
- Enter Joyce Van Patten.
Yes, Joyce, sister of Dick,
the real power behind
the Van Patten empire.
Joyce, like Caligula's
grandmother,
plotting and planning
in the background,
a string of failures
in her wake!
"The Don Rickles Show",
"The Mary Tyler Moore Hour",
"The Good Guys", with Herb
Edelman and Bob Denver,
a show I actually kind of liked
except for the third season
when Rufus got rid of the taxi,
and helped out
more in the diner.
You know, because then
it really kind of--
- Crow, Crow would you
please get to your point?
- Uh, I don't have one.
- That's great.
Okay, c'mon. You're
coming with me.
- Whoa! Whoa!
- We'll be right
back after this.
(upbeat music)
- Then we'll be building
from Willow Lane
right across the airport.
- [Tom] Oh, fun, huh?
- Congratulations, Johnny.
It's gonna be a beauty.
(slurping)
(gulping)
(burping)
- Wonderful party,
Mr. Christensen.
- [Joel] TV's Tony Danza.
- So what do you think?
- I think your shopping
center is premature,
considering you don't
own the ground yet.
- Yeah, well, so are you.
- And how did it go down?
- It didn't go down,
Mr. Christensen.
- [Tom] How did you hear that?
- Like a big fireball.
- I'm sorry, I'm afraid I, I
don't understand your remark.
- Maybe you can understand this.
You're dealing with
real people here.
- With Skiff Stevenston?
- The kind that builds
things and cares about them.
And can't be bought like
your Harvard flunky here.
- D'oh!
- Go ahead.
Blow up another airplane.
Set fire to the
whole damn airport.
Because you're not gonna
move Trumbull or his daughter
four feet off that
patch of earth!
Not if I can help it.
- Way to stick it to the man!
(all whistling and applauding)
- That's not a
familiar name to me.
- Here's a name to get
familiar with. Max Keller.
It's mine, and I want
you to get used to it
because you're gonna
be hearing it a lot.
Probably down at
the DA's office.
- [Tom] Because all the DAs
are named Max Keller now.
- You're not on the
guest list, Mr. Keller.
- Long line of party crashers.
- Mr. Keller walked
into the wrong party.
See him out, will you?
- Enjoy all this, pal.
Because it's just
gonna be a sweet memory
in your eight by six
box with no shadows.
- You're in the next room.
Uh, kegger's next
door, I believe.
- It's okay.
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
Just a little misunderstanding.
- [Tom] Don't worry.
Just a Van Patten,
ladies and gentlemen.
All a part of the act.
(chuckling) It's okay.
- Kyle, I want that
young man in jail.
- [Joel] Then kill him.
- Cheers, Mr. Keller.
- [Tom] Ooh, right
on the gerbil.
- Oh, indoor-outdoor,
this is the best carpet
I've ever been thrown out on.
- I got thrown out.
- I figured.
- [Joel] Uh, I shop here
for my disco shirts.
- Even Rocky had to
take a couple of lessons
before he went back in the
ring with Clubber Lang.
- [Tom] Club, Clubber Lang?
These are fictional characters
you're talking about.
- Now, if I can't
control your passions,
the least I can do is teach you
enough to stay in one piece.
- I thought you'd never offer.
How do you know about Rocky?
You've been out of the
country for over 30 years.
- I saw him on the airplane.
- [Joel] Yeah, I
tried to walk out.
- Hell of a guy, isn't he?
- [Tom] Ba-boom.
Ah.
- You're kidding with
this outfit, right?
- It's traditional.
We'll ease you into
it. Come at me.
No holds barred.
I'm going to kill you.
- [Tom] We're getting into
a whole weird area now.
- You have got to be kidding me.
(Max groaning)
(Tom imitating bones cracking)
- Uncle.
- [Tom] Hm?
- [John] Hone your reflexes
until you react
swifter than thought.
- [Tom] Oh, now you tell me.
- Here, right?
- The center of your
being, inner strength.
- What about getting the outer
strength smacked out of you?
- That's something you should
also be concerned about.
Let's see how you kick.
- [Joel] You know,
black is so slimming
you can't even see
his gut anymore.
- [Tom] Hm, I wonder
what happened?
- Good.
- That was really,
uh, ow! Sonnuva.
- It was still good.
- [Tom] What? Now he's
a, he's a Wallenda?
Yup, yup, he sure is.
- A ninja must have
perfect balance.
- [Joel] Sure. That's
Van Cleef, right?
He can hardly hoist
himself into the van.
- No, this is Lee Van Petit.
(all chuckling)
- [Joel] I don't think so.
- [Tom] Uh, we really
don't need to see that.
Or want to.
David Carradine.
(gentle music)
- And the judges give him a 9.7.
Nice dismount.
- [John] Keep your
eyes on the attack.
- [Joel] Keep your
eye upon the square.
- [Tom] Kaboom.
- [John] From in here, extend.
- Then rake these leaves.
- [John] Expect attack
from any direction.
Concentrate!
- What else you got
in that suitcase?
- [John] When you're ready.
- [Joel] It's a woozle.
His name is Peanut.
- [Tom] Oh, it's Queen
Latifah, of course.
- [Max] I can't hack it.
- Max.
- Yeah, but don't think I'm
walking away from Christensen.
I told him I was gonna
nail him, and I meant it.
Thanks for the lesson.
- That's $45.50 cash.
- You have more tenacity
than I expected,
and speed and courage.
- [Joel] And an agent
who couldn't guarantee
a stunt double.
- It didn't do me
a damn bit of good.
- It showed you can
do more than fight,
and that you're
gonna have to do.
- Now you're beginning
to understand me.
- You have no choice.
You saw Kyle set the
fire at the airport,
you let Christensen
know who you are.
Unless you split town.
- [Tom] All of a sudden it's
a "Barnaby Jones" wrap-up now.
- Fat chance. We'll
have to deal with this.
- We?
- I didn't like what
happened last night.
I didn't like that at all.
- [Tom] It had no texture.
- Maybe the sheriff
would like a visit
from a real, live ninja.
- That could be arranged.
Soon as I get my breath back.
- And some breath mints,
if you don't mind.
- What is it?
- [Joel] Got my breath
back. Feels great.
- A presence.
Let's make that visit.
- [Joel] He is one
spooky mamajama.
(ominous music)
- Than man with the
chainmail face, next.
- [Joel] I was working the day
watch out of Illinois, U.S.A.
♪ You can throw your star at
the man who drives the car ♪
Woo-hoo, woo.
- [Joel] Saw that coming.
Can I have a ride?
Does that bug you?
- I hate magic acts.
- [Tom] Aw, cripes, and
I'm all out of cars!
(Tom beatboxing)
♪ Wonder Woman ♪
♪ Lyle Waggoner ♪
- [Tom] Ooh, thumbcuffs.
- Who was with you last night
when you torched the airport?
- I dunno what you're---
- Name 'em.
Name 'em.
- [Joel] Phrase in the
form of a question.
- Rosetti, Palmer,
Johnson, Donahue.
- Who are they?
- [Tom] The new Monkees.
- [Kyle] Police reserves.
- [Tom] Oh.
- [Max] Every word patched
through to the DA's office.
They'll be by directly.
Now where's Christensen?
- Kid--
- I can get mean and nasty.
My friend behind you, you know,
the one dressed in black
with the samurai sword?
- Louise Nevelson?
- You know how those ninjas are,
always going around
beheading each other.
Barbaric, I know.
To them it's some
kind of ritual.
- [Tom] Uh-huh.
- Know what I mean?
Now where's Christensen?
- [Tom] Ooh, I'm
sorry! I'll talk now!
Ooh, am I scared.
- [Joel] Hey, Phil. How are ya?
- I like a man who
keeps his head.
Don't you?
- Haha. Again you got me.
That is rich.
- [Tom] Next, on a very
special "Trapper John".
- [Joel] Rub the
Mercedes for good luck.
- There's a guard in the
lobby at the front desk.
A lot of monitors
and security guards
at every floor.
- Well, shut up then!
- Boss is on the top floor.
How do we get up there?
- I would suggest
you use the elevator.
- How are you
gonna get up there?
- [John] I'll walk up.
- [Tom] Ew, what did you eat?
- Stairs?
- The building.
- [Max] Sorry I asked.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Hi, I'm here
to kill Mr. Christensen?
- Oh, go right up,
Mr. Van Patten.
- Max Keller to see
Mr. Christensen.
- [Tom] Oh, sorry.
You had a little mustard
down there from lunch.
- You shoulda gone down
like a sack of flour.
Sometimes an old-fashioned
right hand cross comes in handy.
- [Joel] It's a
paperweight and it's a gun.
(all beatboxing)
- Clu Gulager is that
character I can't think of.
- [Joel] "Master Ninja"?
I hate that show.
- Hey, what're you doing there?
- [Tom] Well, like I say,
always keeps a supply
of pegboard hooks
in your pocket.
You never know when
they'll come in handy.
- Jacks master.
- [Tom] In color.
(Tom beatboxing)
- [Tom] Master Ninja.
- Aw, nuts. That's my car.
- [Tom] M-m-m-m-master Ninja.
(upbeat music)
- [Joel] Cover your shame.
[Tom] Ron Cey, ninja doctor.
(Joel gasping)
(Tom humming to
background music)
- Paris!
- That old man can
take care of himself.
- Huh?
Hey, you don't suppose that guy
was supposed to be that guy?
And Queen Latifah!
- [Tom] No way.
- [Joel] Well, whoever he
is, his nose is whistling.
- And he was that
guy? Unbelievable!
He was in every
scene in the movie!
He was Demi Moore!
He was that gerbil! He was--
- [Tom] Crow, Crow,
easy, easy, buddy.
(all whistling)
And just grab the 7-iron.
- [Joel] Clarence
the cross-eyed ninja.
- [Tom] He who removeth
the sword from its sheath
shall be the rightwiseborn
king of England.
- [Joel] Conhuge
Co. welcomes you.
(all whistling)
- Hey, Lee.
You wanna check those
bags at the door?
(all chuckling)
- [Tom] Woo.
- I think I'll check my
credit rating while I'm here.
(whistling)
- [Joel] Hi, I'm Bonnie,
your Conhuge Co. operator.
Oh, back to work. (chuckling)
- [Tom] The ninja creeps
in on little cat feet.
- Am I in the right movie?
Hey, Lee, come over here a sec.
- [Tom] Wait.
Whose theme music is that?
- [Joel] Can he sneeze
through that thing?
He's wearing a Joe Namath
netted slingshot brief
on his face.
- Yeah, meanwhile Timothy's
having a Nam flashback.
- [Joel] Ooh.
- [Tom] And over here
of the 30th floor
of the Ernest and Julio
Gallo wine cellar.
- [Max] Christensen.
(gun firing)
(glass breaking)
- Who is it!?
- Helicopter's a late, huh?
Too bad.
Your lawyer, Mr.
Havilland and Sheriff Kyle
are both under arrest.
- [Joel] Oh, they are?
I, I have no idea
what's going on.
- [Max] But of
course you know that.
That's why you're
leaving in such a hurry.
- [Tom] His office
looks like a Chi Chi's.
- Hey, bring me those nachos!
- [Max] Sometimes
things just don't
work out the way you planned.
- [Tom] Oh, and on top of it
all, he's a ventriloquist.
- I'm glad we had this chance
to meet again, Mr. Keller.
Otherwise your grandstand
play last night
wouldn't mean a thing, would it?
- [Joel] 'Cause it
ain't got no swing.
- [Tom] And your friends are
the only creeps in this place.
- It's better late than never.
- [Max] Just one question.
- [Tom] Can I use
your fax machine?
- And what would that be?
- [Max] How do you plan
on getting up on the roof?
- [Tom] Hmm.
- You really think you
can stop me, Keller?
- [Max] Just keep talking, pal.
(gun firing)
- Oh, it's a
ventriloquist pistol.
- [Tom] (chuckling) Say
hello to folks, Remington.
- I got a bad feeling about
that knickknack shelf.
- [Joel] Uh-huh. I see it.
- [Tom] Kids, what was that?
- [Joel and Crow] Nothing, mom.
- [Joel] Good thing he
studied with that ninja
for those 10 minutes.
- Check out, Jack.
- [Tom] Wow, this
movie is clueless.
Woohoo!
- Yeah, 'cause there's, he died.
Meanwhile in the other
incomprehensible plot,
Queen Latifah takes a--
(Tom humming background music)
- [John] I've been
expecting you.
- [Ninja] A ninja does
not betray his destiny.
You will die.
- [Tom] Okay, fine.
Just wait a second.
Let me park the tape drive here.
- [Joel] You didn't pay
for your leather mug!
(Tom imitating arrow twanging)
- Why didn't he just kill him
when he was watching
him from the tree?
- [Joel] Those things
are $4.50 apiece.
- [Tom] (chuckling) Okay.
One more, and then
to bed for you.
- I'll take him.
(ninja shouting)
- Okay, you take him now.
- [Joel] Huzzah.
- [Tom] Oof.
Okay, okay, knock it off.
You're getting
obnoxious about it now.
(both shouting)
- [Joel] You know,
Doris is gonna be irked
if she sees this
mess in the morning.
- [Tom] Yup.
Ah, there go the
financials for December.
- I, I'll take him.
- [Tom] Make 'em laugh!
Make 'em laugh!
- [Joel] The nunchuks, Luke.
Use the nunchuks.
- [Tom] Trust your feelings.
- Oh, a leather punch. Cool.
(both shouting)
- [Tom] Ooh.
- [Joel] That thing's
got everything.
- [Tom] A lot of yelling.
- Oh, now you've ruined the
whole ambience of the room.
- [Tom] I'll take it
from here. I'll clean up.
- [Ninja] You are a ninja.
Kill your enemy as you've
always done, kyojin.
- What? A Kirin?
Ah, yeah. I could
go for a Kirin.
- [John] Never again.
- [Joel] No more
raspberry commies.
- [Ninja] There will
be another time.
They will be coming for you.
- If you could just
take this off my chest,
and move it to the
side, it would be most--
- [John] I'll be waiting.
- [Joel] In all the
old familiar places.
(all groaning)
- [Tom] I always do that.
- Don't turn your
back on that guy.
- You see what he
did to me last time?
- He won't fight again tonight.
I'm certain.
An artery was severed.
- [Tom] Boy, and he's
not even bleeding.
- Who is he?
- Okasa, now a ninja master.
Was one of my students.
- Sent to kill you.
What ancient little
gadget did you use
to sever Okasa's artery?
- My fingers.
- [Joel] Sticky fingers.
- Sorry I asked.
- [Tom] Not designed as
a real sword, only a toy.
Darn!
- Mendoza!
- [Joel] Epilogue.
- [Max] Holly knows
your daughter.
She's in Atlanta.
- [John] Is she all right?
- Find that out
when you get there.
I can take you that far.
- [Tom] Hm.
I hope she's into
big-ass medallions.
- It's pretty.
- Symbol of my household.
- I got it from Bob Vila.
- It's what Okasa wanted.
- I don't get it.
- For another man to possess it
would mean I was
no longer alive.
- You guys got your
own set of rules.
No one else can play, huh?
- [Joel] Yeah, and I'm
always the banker, punk.
- I was taught the secrets
of the ninjas for a purpose.
So that I might
pass them on the way
my master passed them on to me.
- And I end up with a
has-been from "White Shadow".
- What good is a ninja
teacher without a student?
- [Tom] Well, those
who can't ninja, teach.
(mellow music)
- [Joel] Hey, here
comes Betty Jo.
Hi!
- [Tom] Hi, Betty Jo.
- I've met people
way cooler than you!
- [Tom] Let's roll, folks.
- Say hi to the Brat Pack!
- Look out for that
thing, what the hell?
- [Joel] I think
it's over there.
- You're getting scary again.
(upbeat music)
- Yes, yes.
Found myself in
Japan after the war.
Boy, talk about tranquil, whew!
Let me tell ya.
But anyway, I got
to know some ninjas.
Hey, they're great guys,
and they're thick
as flies over there.
Well, one thing led to
another, and I found myself--
- Yaa!
You're impressed at
Occidental Roser.
Me and my scary theme
music will follow you
and your plastic katana sword
to the ends of the Earth!
And then I will-
(both laughing)
- Come here!
You and your cheap,
cheap, Japanese accent!
- You can tell, you can
tell by my theme music
that I'm a typical American.
You wanna see the
way we leave a bar?
Whoa!
- The power of my music is
the weakness of my music!
You with your crummy
Oriental accent!
Grr.
- There's nothing like a
good old-fashioned left hook!
- Ow!
- Hey, cool it, you guys.
- Hey, hey, Gypsy, what
are you supposed to be?
- Gigi.
- Don't you wanna be Demi Moore?
- It's show--
- [Forrester] Don't even
think about it, Frank.
Send him the movie.
- Time.
(Klaxon blaring)
(all shouting)
- We got movie
sign, it's coming!
(energetic dance music)
- Uh, could we see
a menu, please?
- That's Kelly Pattersen.
She was the girl standing
next to your daughter.
- [Joel] Sleep!
- Her old man runs this place.
I'll try and catch
her after this dance.
We don't wanna
integrate you too fast
into modern-day society.
- [Tom] Good point.
- All right. You go
talk the pretty girl.
I'll talk to her father.
- What a pal.
- Any time.
- I love the way they banter.
Such chemistry!
- [Tom] Uh, Miss,
could we please
get some bread or something?
- She owes me $5. (sniffling)
♪ Staying a guy, staying a guy ♪
Jack Perkins?
- No!
- Oh, yeah.
- Jack, no!
- [Tom] Oh my.
- [Joel] Hey, what
happened to Demi Moore?
This is getting weird.
- Oh yeah.
- [Tom] Oh, swing it, Lee.
Woo, look at him go.
Oh my god.
What happened to her other leg?
Oh.
- There it is.
(audience cheering)
- [Tom] Woo. Woo.
- Mrs. Ironside in color.
(whistling)
- She's something, isn't she?
- A true spirit,
permeated with joy.
And she moves great.
- You betcha.
- [Joel] We're bald
and we're bonding.
- Where's Jill?
- She's in the kitchen.
- She's watching old
movies, Mr. Pattersen.
- Mr. Pattersen?
- I'll be right with you.
- [Tom] He's a queer duck, eh?
(audience cheering)
- [Tom] Woo. Woo. Woo.
- I, uh, hate to burst your
bubble, but she stinks.
- No one's allowed backstage.
- [Joel] It's Alan Thicke!
- [Tom] Oh.
- Oh, uh, Kim.
- Just enjoy the show.
- Hi, we're here
to buy everything.
- [Joel] Fusion jazz
is for all cultures.
(Tom humming)
- [Tom] Now that's one way
to get service, I suppose.
- [Max] Perhaps you can help us.
- [Joel] Candy-coated
popcorn peanuts and a prize.
- We've come to
see Mr. Pattersen.
- In the office over there.
- Thank you so much.
- [Tom] Oh no, thank you.
- Looks like Clarence
Thomas's wife.
- [Tom] It does.
Oh, Lee, don't worry.
She's used to it.
The Kennedys come here a lot.
- You'd think with
all the roughnecks
we get in this place
I'd be used to it.
- You were right to be afraid.
- [Joel] Be very afraid.
- [Tom] My, but you
area sensitive male.
See you.
- Oh, it's the other
side of the mountain.
- [Charlie] What
are you doing, Jill?
- [Jill] I'm watching you
and Mother dance the waltz
from "Lady Be Good".
- Down in front, old man!
- [Tom] Ah, you know, Fred
Astaire and Ginger Rogers.
Love them.
- Look at that lift.
Look at the way you moved.
You were so graceful.
- [Joel] Yet so effeminate.
- I'll just bet you
had Mr. Astaire shaking
in his dancing pumps.
- I was his dresser actually.
- I don't think he
was shaking too hard.
- You think it's kind
of sicko for the leader
of a wheelchair brigade
to get such a charge
out of watching
other people dance?
- Yes, actually.
- [Jill] I don't mean
the way my sister dances.
That's not dancing.
- It's typing.
- That's aerobics.
Now what you did was dancing.
Bet you could still do it, too.
If you really wanted to.
- [Joel] Maybe if I had a hip.
- Or if he was hip.
- You're right, dad.
With some hot towels on my
legs at half hourly intervals,
couple of FDR canes.
- Oh, yes.
Oh, yeah.
- I might be able to
manage a couple of steps.
- A cane didn't hurt
Mr. Astaire's career.
- [Joel] Oh, bite me.
- Don't you just
hate dealing with it?
An ex-hoofer with two daughters.
- [Tom] Hooker? Oh, hoofer.
- One wheels, the
other cartwheels.
- One is shy and retiring,
and, uh, one has a smart mouth.
- [Tom] Ooh, touche.
- My sister, shy and retiring?
The decade's answer
to Isadora Duncan?
- [Joel] What?
She wears scarves?
- That's angry Jill.
- Sorry. I'm bitter.
- I wonder what she calls me.
- Gimp?
- [Joel] Oh, that's mean.
- Isn't that what
you call yourself?
- Hey, now. Wait a minute.
I took two steps yesterday.
- [Tom] Time to go, honey.
- I know.
- Oh.
This is my favorite part.
This is your audition
for the dancing pirate.
This, this is a blast.
- You were really gadding it up.
- [Joel] We'd like to
buy her wheelchair.
- Mr. Pattersen,
how good to meet you
in person after all
those phone calls.
I'm Jonathan Chan,
and this is Mr. Lika.
- Uh, are you related
to Mr. Phlegm?
- Would you excuse
us, young lady?
Your father and I have some
important business to discuss.
- In a pig's eye.
- Jill, come on.
- [Tom] One talks
of pigs, one sweats.
- Watch your feet, gentlemen.
I'm lethal with this
thing. You mind?
- [Tom] Ooh, my foot.
Oof.
- So let's talk business.
- There's a little
trouble up front.
- Big China.
- [Max] While Attila
the Hun was distracted,
I saw my chance
to get backstage.
This was gonna be easy.
- [Joel] At first.
- [Tom] Oops.
(women chattering)
- Hey, can I get
a pencil in here?
Okay, give me the number.
Okay.
- Thank god I lost my
peripheral vision in the war.
- [Tom] Hey, what is this?
"Dream On" all of a sudden?
- Hey.
Don't take your
hand from your eyes
you're gonna walk into the wall.
- You got a D cup or,
it's decaf. Decaf.
- You really shouldn't
be back here.
Our bouncer has a small
personality problem.
- Who? Attila the Hun?
We're pals.
Kelly Pattersen, I'm Max Keller.
Looking for a girl.
- [Joel] New or used?
- If the stars are in the
right places it'd be you.
The name's Terry.
You know her?
- Uh, no dancer
here named Terry.
Look, we're on a break now,
and I've gotta go meet someone.
Sorry.
- Yeah, but I--
- Sorry.
- Just take a look at
this picture and see if--
- Is it my breath?
- [Max] Wasn't as
easy as I thought.
- [Tom] And it's
time for the bouncer
to get into his spandex leotard.
- [Joel] Mwah!
- Kelly did mention a small
personality problem of yours.
- [Tom] Yeah, you
hate Van Pattens.
- It's the Battle of
the Network Has-beens!
- [Tom] Woo.
- [Joel] Yeah, that's for
all of the Van Pattens
you've kicked out of bars.
- How do you like this, pal?
Here's a little warning.
- [Joel] Uh-oh. Seven
years bad acting.
- Need more practice.
- I told you eight is enough!
- [Max] So seven years bad luck.
Meanwhile, the
master was getting us
into even more trouble.
- [Tom] Snapping off car
antennas in the parking lot.
- [Joel] You ninja
masters blend in so well.
- [Tom] Especially in discos.
- Like the roots of a great
oak, we take hold where we can.
- The only protection I need
is from people like you.
Now get out.
- Isn't everyone
here really phony?
- I cannot move.
- [John] That's an unusual
insignia on your ring.
- An ancient household
going back for centuries.
- Knights of Columbus?
- Yes, I know.
- [Joel] You an
Iron Butterfly man?
- We've been told
to leave. Let's go.
- Come on, man.
That Jack Perkins
guy really scares me.
- I may leave when
he lets me go.
- [Tom] Tonight
on "Ninja Master",
Lee Van Cleef and Sho Kosugi
in a deadly game
of cat and mouse.
- The old man hired you.
- I am not for hire.
- We are all for
hire in dark times.
- The dark times have gone.
- [Tom] Are you guys speaking
in haiku all of a sudden?
Whoa.
- Night is always
with us, master.
- Could we get to the
point? Geez, what a drip.
(mellow music)
- [Joel] What? She's giving
herself her autograph?
- Taking her own order.
- Here's her last address.
Oh!
Oh, he's so adorable.
- Spooky chick.
- One glimpse of
those blue eyes,
and every girl falls for him.
I've gotta learn his technique.
So when's the last
time you saw Terry?
- [Tom] Terry Thomas?
- About a week ago. Look.
I hope your friend isn't
expecting to find--
- No!
- She's really messed up.
Drugs.
- [Tom] Yeah, she
ran out. (laughing)
- So how'd you get
past good old Attila?
- He carries some cute little
tricks around with him.
Like this.
- [Joel] Oh, that's the
blade from my mixer.
- He's just leaving.
- Here's your gerbil.
- [Max] It's daylight already.
I didn't realize we
were in there so long.
- [Tom] Hey, hey,
that's Nancy Kulp!
Nancy Kulp just walked by!
- What the hell
was that all about?
- This is not a toy.
You only throw a shuriken
against another human being
in self-defense.
You ever again take another
weapon out of my case,
you be prepared to use
it against your enemy,
even if it's me.
- [Joel] And stop
using my toothbrush.
- I'd rather not.
- Not yet anyway.
- I guess you don't respect
what you don't understand.
- I don't respect why
this movie was made.
- [Tom] Amen.
- Kelly's address
and phone number.
- [Joel] All right.
- I managed to get
that much before you
hauled me out of there.
The other address
is your daughter's.
- Kelly knows her?
- She knows a girl named Terry,
who used to be a
dancer and a pilot.
- [Tom] Terry and the Pilots!
- It doesn't necessarily
mean she's your daughter.
- It's a radio show.
- Let's find out.
- I'll do the driving.
You fill the Mitsubishi
with shurikens.
- What?
You wanna translate
that for us, Tim?
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Get a windsock
for the microphone
next time you do
an outdoor scene.
Come on! I don't understand.
- They're leaving now.
- [Joel] I know. I'm
sitting next to you.
- Maxcv Now comes the fun
part. Riding with a ninja.
- [Tom] We'll be
the judge of that.
"Chevy Van", a Quinn
Martin production.
- [Max] We're being followed!
- [Tom] Of course we are.
We're in an action-packed
made-for-TV movie.
- Quick!
Take a turn here on Steven
J. Cannell Boulevard!
(Tom humming)
- Don't tell me why
they're following us.
I like surprises.
- Well, here's a surprise.
You're already canceled!
- [All] Flubber!
- [Tom] Woohoo!
- [Tom] Woohoohoohoohoo!
- Remember "Bullitt"?
Think of me as Paul Newman.
- Steve McQueen.
- Oh, right.
- Ha. Yup.
Paul Newman, Steve McQueen,
Timothy Van Patten.
The legends.
Ha.
- [Tom] We turn here at
David Hasselhoff Boulevard.
- You know what they're doing?
They're just trying
to keep away from
the set of "What's Up, Doc?"
- [Joel] Oh, back, we're
at a Rockford turn,
or is that a Starsky?
- Who are those guys?
- Assassins.
- Sent by Okasa?
- Bob Costas?
- A man like Okasa. A ninja.
- You just naturally run
into these fellow ninjas
everywhere you go?
I mean, can't you
just shake hands?
Do you have to show you
can outkill each other?
- He must believe
I was in the club
to help Charlie Pattersen.
- Well, what's his problem?
(gun firing)
Tell me later.
- [Tom] Yeah, but within
that next half-hour, please.
- [Joel] Hey, this is
a school zone! Please!
(gun firing)
- He's got a silencer on.
- [Tom] Oh no!
They're being chased
by David Sanborn!
(gun firing)
- Oh, Routine 27. They
fall for it every time.
(tires squealing)
- Pull over when you can.
- Pull over?
- [Joel] Ah, I gotta to
the little ninja's room.
- Throw a star.
- [Tom] Hold it.
Yep, yep.
Once again, the pursuing vehicle
is driven by stupid people.
- [Max] I didn't know
what he was gonna do.
- So I did a voiceover.
- [Max] And I don't
think I wanted to know.
- [Joel] Hey, if
the van's a-rocking.
Haha.
- I feel like snorkeling.
Pick me up in an hour.
- [Joel] Well, it is
a good way to blend in
in San Francisco.
Dress like a mime.
- [Tom] Calvin Klein jeans.
- [Joel] Where's Demi Moore?
This movie's gone off in a
whole different direction.
- Where did he go?
- I hear his theme music.
He's around here somewhere.
- [Tom] Oh, he went
to Outward Bound.
- I'll back up.
- [Joel] He's a
lineman for the county.
- Oh, he's gonna make
crank phone calls.
- [Joel] You know, this
has all the continuity
of a fever dream.
- [Tom] Hey, look.
The stunt guy's
got a face mask on.
What's going on?
- I wouldn't touch this
movie with a 12-foot pole.
- [Tom] A 50-foot pole.
- Like polenta?
- [Joel] Ladies and
gentlemen, Lee Van Cleef.
- [Tom] Yeah right. (chuckling)
- Thomas, Seward, Edward, cat.
- [Tom] Hey, you think
that guy up on the wire's
what we're looking-
- [Joel] Nah. Nah, couldn't be.
- [Joel] Bring it in.
That's right.
Bring it in, just like that.
- [Tom] Let Hertz
put you in the--
- Go, Ninja Master,
on top of the car.
- [Joel] Hi, could you give
me a lift to the gas station?
- Now this is somewhat similar
I mean the first epi, I mean,
the first part of the movie.
- [Tom] The movie, yes.
- Silly String Ninja, in color.
(all laughing)
- [Tom] That's really rich.
This is starting to get
a little unbelievable.
- This is no place
for a convertible!
♪ TV movie ♪
♪ TV movie, TV movie ♪
- Oh no, a Montero.
- [Joel] All right.
Drop the steering
wheel, and come with us.
- You'll find me pleasing.
- [Tom] I squint,
therefore I am.
- Sho Kosugi pops the clutch
and tells Van Cleef
to eat his dust!
- [Joel] Oh, ninjas
never had those.
- [Tom] Damn. He
knows Doug Henning.
- You all right?
- [Joel] Yeah, but
I'm out 20 bucks.
Let's head back to
the magic store.
- The steering wheel
gag was a classic.
gag was classic.
- Diving school.
- You call the cops?
- And tell them you
were the driver that
forced another car off the pier?
- [Tom] D'oh.
- Maybe we should pass.
- [Tom] A stone.
- Now you gonna tell
me who these guys are?
- It's a family affair.
They're moving out of Chinatown
into a new neighborhood,
only Charlie Pattersen's
a stubborn old man.
And he won't pay protection.
- No wonder you liked him.
- [Joel] Hey, hey.
Zing me again.
- Well, our ex-hoofer
doesn't understand
who he's dealing with.
He's gonna have to be convinced.
Let's go.
- Meanwhile, in Las Vegas.
- Oh, I had the Buddha Delight.
It was real reasonable
here at Golden Pagoda.
- Our dear Mr. Pattersen
appears to have
a more powerful friend
than I imagined.
- That's a nice place.
They must be good thugs.
- We need a little
more to bargain with.
- [Joel] We'll send
them Pink Lady and Jeff.
- Like his daughter.
Pick up the dancer.
- [Tom] Oh, that
shouldn't be too hard.
- [Joel] PJ Truffleberry's,
try the Phantoozler.
♪ We're in this love together ♪
♪ I got a love that ♪
(clearing throat) Time.
If I hear anymore John
Kander, I'll kill myself.
- [Joel] What is
this? "Ice Castles"?
- Tonight on
"Rendezvous Theater".
- [Tom] Oh. Oh, baby.
Baby, I love you so much, baby.
You can dance with me, baby.
I'll still love you.
- He's doing Barry White.
- Yeah, Barry good.
- [Tom] Ooh, baby.
- Are you padding out the film?
Cut it out!
- [Tom] Hey, check
out my AA medallion.
Spent the morning 12-stepping
the Van Patten kid.
- Okay, honey.
Now you're just
being self-indulgent.
- Thanks a lot.
I'll be back out at 11.
She is one spooky chick.
- Mm-hm.
- [Joel] Look at
what she's wearing.
She looks like she
works at Arby's.
- [Tom] May I take
your order, please?
(upbeat music)
(somber music)
- Get up!
Get up, walk!
You've never given up
on anything in your,
well, actually I haven't
know you that long.
♪ Walk 'cause you're
filled with love ♪
♪ Walk 'cause you have
to believe in yourself ♪
- A very special
Hallmark Hall of Fame.
♪ Walk 'cause you want
to walk and see it ♪
- [Joel] Whoa, she's been shot!
(all gasping)
- [Tom] Lee, you can
jump in anytime here.
- C'mon! Give me 20!
C'mon. One, that's
one. Half of one.
- [Tom] He knows you're alone.
- [Joel] Boy, that parquet
floor must really sting.
- Butter.
- I can't do this.
- No kidding.
- Yes, you can.
It comes from the heart.
- Who's there?
- He's right in front of
you for crying out loud.
- A hand reaching
out of the darkness.
Sometimes we can do
things for strangers.
- [Tom] I've always depend
on the kindness of strangers.
- [Joel] Will somebody speak up?
- You can do it.
I make up my own steps.
- What?
- Huh?
- Louder!
- Imagine a silken cord-
- Not closer.
- Being spun out
from here, your ki.
One more step.
- [Tom] Oh, I see
that helps. Thank you.
I missed most of what you said,
but I'm sure it was
supposed to be encouraging.
- You can do it.
- She's transfixed
by his dewlap.
- [Joel] Ah, you drooled
all over my turtleneck.
- [Tom] You were fantastic, Lee.
- I'd appreciate it if you'd
take me back to my chair now.
- I've been in this
restaurant for 10 minutes,
and I've yet to be seated.
- [Tom] Doesn't anybody
sleep in this movie?
It's like 10 in the morning
now, for crying out loud.
- [Joel] Uh, mind if
I ask you a question?
Just what the heck do you have
to do with the plot anyhow?
- [Tom] Subplot.
- Look, you, uh, did your
good deed for the day.
Sorry it didn't work out
for either one of us.
- Nah, he's going for
his ninja merit badge.
- If you're here to see the
dancing, you're a little late.
My sister Kelly's departed.
- [Joel] Uh, keep talking.
I can't remember my lines.
- Must be tough.
- What?
Having a big sister that
moves like an angel?
It's a trip.
I watch her every night.
- Hey, that's your business.
- Gimps get, uh, very vicarious.
- [Tom] The correct term
is physically challenged.
- Why are you here?
- I came to see your father.
- About a horse.
- Who are you?
- [Jill] John Peter McAllister.
- [Joel] John Jacob
Jingelheimer Schmidt.
- [Tom] That's my name, too.
- I'm Jill Pattersen, the--
- Gimp.
- Geez.
- Ouch.
- Handles are dangerous things,
- [Joel] I know, love handles.
- And once you start walking,
you won't be called
a gimp any longer.
- [Tom] Well, you
shouldn't be calling her
a gimp now, dickweed.
- Well, those steps
did feel pretty good.
I kept weight on 'em
like I was putting
one foot right in
front of the other.
- That's pretty
much the concept.
- Like I was walking, you know?
- Looked that way.
- [Tom] Ah, here's Jack Perkins.
- Ah, Pops, there's
someone here to see you.
- It's the battle
of the turtlenecks,
and Lee's not wearing one.
- You are very good with her.
- She'll walk up here first.
When she does that, you'll know.
- You seem to have taken quite
an interest in my family.
- You can't handle that
protection thing by yourself,
not against those boys.
- What kinda skull
wax do you use?
- They're more than
just gangsters,
or even the Tong Sect.
They're ninja.
I'll explain. Where's Kelly?
- [Tom] Uh, at her day job.
- [Max] The master had
sent me to protect Kelly.
But I wasn't fast enough.
- [Joel] Gym socks! No!
(all coughing)
- Hey, I was gonna do that.
- [Joel] Timothy Van
Patten is "Hard To Kill".
- [Tom] Now where's that sock?
Ugh, it's all crunchy. Huh?
- Excellent.
I see that your master
has found himself a pupil.
I will attempt to be
a worthy adversary.
- [Joel] Haggar Action Slacks.
- [Tom] Got the whole
action suit there.
That's for "The White Shadow".
I hated that show.
- [Joel] And that's
for "Eight Is Enough".
Tell your dad.
- [Tom] Now where's that sock?
(speaking foreign language)
(whistling)
- Nothing going on.
Nothing at all.
- [Joel] It's the
people under the stairs.
- What a pity your lessons
had to end so abruptly.
- [Tom] Well, maybe he can
take his ninja equivalency exam
and get a certificate.
(mumbling)
- PJ Truffleberry's.
Try the Pantoozler.
- Four fractured ribs.
- [Tom] Geez, Check out the
chromedomes in this scene.
- Too fast.
Couldn't move.
- No way you coulda
stopped them.
(phone ringing)
- [Joel] Hello,
1-900-DANCE-BELT.
- Mr. Pattersen.
- [Tom] New Jersey?
- I regret the measures
you forced us to take.
However, I'm certain that
after our initial
misunderstanding,
the business between
us will be gentlemanly.
You'll withdraw $20,000
from the bank today.
- I haven't got that kind
of money to withdraw.
- Oh, some bonds cashed
in, some, some shares sold.
- Yeah, some shares sold. Yeah.
- A little austerity's good
for the soul, Mr. Pattersen.
Speak to your daughter,
who is in good health,
if a little scared.
But that's only natural.
- Here. It's for
you. It's your dad.
- [Joel] Daddy,
there's a boy outside.
His name is Wang.
- I'm fine.
Don't give him anything.
Don't!
- [Tom] No, at least wait until
they cut a chunk of my ear off.
- No harm will come to
her, because both you and I
understand that you're
going to cooperate.
- Yeah, cooperate.
Yeah, pretty much.
- And the man we
saw in your club,
he will leave San Francisco.
You have until 3:00
this afternoon.
- [Joel] But that's
when my soap's on.
- I'll get the money.
- I know you will.
We will call your
office at 3:00.
And please, don't disappoint
me, Mr. Pattersen.
I so hate to be disappointed.
Bye, sir.
- [Tom] Hey, don't pad
your part, Desi. C'mon.
- Man, she cries at
the opening of a bank.
- We'll find her.
She's gotta be somewhere
Chinatown, right?
- Many doors will be closed.
Few will hear you.
All you'll see in
their eyes is fear.
- [Joel] 'Cause they
know your father.
- Then we'll search from
one end to the other.
- Not by 3:00.
Can you withdraw
that kind of money?
- I'll have to put
a lien on the club.
- [Tom] Oh, what they
hey, tip it over.
- But I can do it.
- I don't believe
what I'm hearing.
- [Tom] I do.
- You mean we're just
going to give in to them?
Pay the ransom?
Sell out?
Is that what a real
ninja would do?
- [Joel] I'm not a real
ninja, but I play one on TV.
- Illusion.
Give them what they expect
and they'll believe it.
- What do we really do?
- The unexpected.
- I don't like this.
- [Max] They'll see us coming.
- Not if we send
the right person.
Jill, I need your help.
- All right, ready, guys?
- Yo.
(Crow speaking foreign language)
- I'm Joel Robinson.
- And I'm Tom Servo.
- And I'm TV's
wisecracking Crow.
- And who can forget
this lovable gag?
It's my classic
self-defense device
for farmers, nun-clucks.
Get it?
- Now that's a
special memory, eh?
- Now, in the spirit
of today's movie,
"Master Ninja," we've come
up with a whole gaggle
of lovable chuck ideas.
- You see, we've taken the
classic Japanese nunchaku,
or the bastardized
American nunchuck,
and spun 'em around!
- Right, exactly.
- Yeah, after all,
what is a nunchuck
but two things on a chain?
- Yeah.
- Right.
So for instance, a clumsy
ninja would use these.
Thumb-chucks.
- Yeah, also known
as dumb-chucks.
- Good one.
- Oh, and for
Dominican ninjas who
are dressed in black
anyway, we offer nunchuks,
- Woo hoo.
Benedict's got all the dominoes.
Sorry, ladies.
But you know, for meat-lovers,
they're gonna flip over
these classic ground-chucks.
Yeah. Woo hoo.
- All right, heat
'em up, eat 'em up,
then summon the earl up
with these up-chucks.
- Oh.
- Ew.
Hey, drinking man?
- It's all in fun.
- Junior at St. Cloud State?
Hey, knock your friends
on they sorry butts
with a trendy Captain
Morgan Spiced rum-chuck.
- Aikiba.
- Oh, blow the man down.
Say, Crow, and
speaking of butts,
there's no better segue
into my own butt-chucks.
- Oh, come on.
- That's, that's
a little bit rich.
- Now that is a little too far.
- Oh, lighten up, you guys.
It's just a couple
of rubber gag butts.
Geez.
- Well, you know what?
It's so easy, why don't you
write some chuck ideas at home?
As long as it's done
tongue-in-cheek.
- Yeah, in fact, why don't you?
Hey, mail your chuck
ideas to Chucks,
care of Mystery Science
Theater 3000 Information Club,
PO Box 5325, Hopkins,
Minnesota, 55343.
You'll be glad you did.
Maybe we'll read
them on the air.
- Yeah.
We're even going to help
you get started here.
For instance, you might call
these lamby soft weapons
of vengeance chuck-wooleries.
- We'll be back in
two minutes, in two.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, it's Mrs. Ironside.
Tonight's episode, Teahouse
of the August Murder.
- [Joel] Well, it's a
good thing Chinatown's
wheelchair accessible, you know?
- Yeah, here's hoping.
- Oh, uh, hi.
I'm selling candy bars, mister,
for my school marching band.
- Let me see the money.
- [Tom] Will this ransom
be cash or charge?
- $20,000, that's almost enough
for a month's rent
in San Francisco.
- Where's my sister?
- Safe.
- This is supposed to be an
exchange, the money for Kelly.
- Your sister will
be returned to you.
- [Joel] Oh, we sent
her regular mail.
Might take about a day.
- Oof, oh.
He hit the assistant director.
- [Tom] Ouch.
Ooh.
- If I could only get
out of this chair.
- [Tom] Hey, if we could
only get out of this movie.
- Be glad that you can't.
- [Joel] Hm?
(whistling)
Hop in.
You'll have to throw that
baby seat in the back.
My wife's got the Cadillac.
- [Tom] Hm, nice car.
Oh, wait.
Looks like trouble
with the transmission.
- [Joel] You're next.
- Ninja Auto Mechanic, in color.
♪ Da da da ♪
- Hey, what's that fool
doing under that car?
(mumbling)
- [Joel] See that?
What a dickweed.
- Let's hope they fall
for the unexpected.
- Ow, ow, ow. Bad idea.
Ow.
- [Joel] Hey, mister,
your ninja's dragging.
- [All] Flubber!
- [Tom] Now, how
much would you pay
for these patented
Ginsu Ninja Grippers?
Wait, there's more.
- What happened to his bad back?
- [Tom] Oh, no, no.
That was in the last
episode, oh, I mean,
the last half of the movie.
- [Joel] You know, I get the
feeling everybody in this movie
had a bad childhood.
I don't know, but--
- [Tom] Yep.
- Ugh, water.
Ugh, water.
(soft exotic music)
- [Tom] Anwar Sadat, in color.
- Stop that.
- It's fun.
- [Joel] Yep, they're
really inconspicuous.
Yep, can't, just blending in.
- [Tom] Wait a minute.
I had one of those
in a goldfish bowl.
- [John] Maybe
that's the way in.
- [Joel] It's a crazy idea,
but it just might wok,
I mean, work.
- So like a jerk, he hangs
under the truck and gets all--
- Something's happened
to your friend.
- Not to him.
- I didn't even see him.
- That doesn't mean
he wasn't there.
(phone ringing)
- [Tom] (beeping)
Hi, I'm Jim Rockford.
I'm not in right now, but--
- [Joel] Yeah, it's a
phone. I'm almost certain.
- [Tom] Charlie Pattersen.
Charlie Pattersen.
Starring Pat Carroll.
- $20,000 as promised.
You didn't disappoint
me after all.
- When will my
daughter be returned?
- Hey, you said we could
have her 'til Wednesday.
- I understand from
the bank you had
to take out a lien on your club.
(tutting)
Too much of a financial
strain in these hard times.
- Hey, blame it
on Ronald Reagan.
- You will sign the
lien over to me.
I will pay it.
The club will then
be mine, of course.
Oh, but you must stay on.
The customers would
be so disappointed.
- If that's what it'll take
to bring my daughter back.
- [Joel] This sounds
like extortion.
- Have it arranged
by tomorrow morning.
She'll be with you for lunch.
- It would be fun
to run a nightclub.
I think it would be
fun to run a nightclub.
- You stay here at the club,
and we'll both be back
tonight with Kelly.
He's not doing this alone.
- [Tom] Mm-mm. No way.
Oh, letter opener.
(Crow mumbling)
- I thought this
was a partnership.
- Too dangerous.
- That little chase in
the streets this morning,
you don't suppose that had just
a small element of danger in it?
- [Joel] What?
- [Max] What am
I, the chauffeur?
- I told you, when you're ready.
- I'll tell you what
I'm not ready for.
I'm not ready to
see Kelly killed.
I'm not ready to see you
go off into the sunset
against that pack of wolves.
I'm not ready to be shot at,
driven at, or
kicked in the face.
- And I'm not ready to
take acting lessons.
- But you are ready
to get killed?
- [Joel] Well, yeah.
- With you around, how
could you let that happen?
- I suppose you'd
only follow me.
- Believe it.
- I believe it. You ready
for your ninja robes?
- Are they as goofy as yours?
- I'm still working up to that.
Though I do have a black outfit.
Jeans and a turtleneck.
How about a weapon?
- Hold it.
- [Tom] No, not by the edge! No!
- It'll make you feel better.
- [Joel] If you put
it in the right place.
- I wouldn't think of it.
- [Tom] Meanwhile,
in downtown Fargo.
Let's see.
Oh, Beverly's Hills.
(Tom beatboxing)
- [Joel] You know, I've
got the money, the club,
and the girl, yet I feel empty.
Why? Why?
- Bring the girl to me.
- [Tom] I desire to discuss
philosophy with her.
- [Joel] Ninja bow and
arrow sold separately.
- [All] Shh!
- [Max] I knew he'd find a
way to get me on a tightrope.
- [Tom] Timothy Van Patten,
master of the
non-sequitur voice-over.
(suspenseful music)
(glass breaking)
- [Tom] Hey, what's
going on out there?
- Hey, some of us work
for a living, you know?
- [Tom] Shut up! Quiet! Shh!
- [Max] It's getting
back that worries me.
- You hear anything?
- [Tom] Hm? No.
- [Joel] All right,
Coltrane live in Japan.
- [Kelly] Someone, please help!
Help!
- [Tom] Smart hostages,
foolish choices.
Today on "Oprah".
- I hear you're
quite a performer.
Dance for me.
- All right.
- I really want to direct.
- You're a dancer! Dance!
- Well, you're an actor.
Act!
(lively dance music)
- [Joel] Did you say dance?
(Tom beatboxing)
- [Tom] You don't mean it.
Put your heart into it.
- I want to get physical,
physical. (sobbing)
- [Tom] Uh, uh, never mind.
Do you write short
stories maybe?
- [Joel] This is wild, I swear.
- I can't. I can't.
- [All] We know. We know.
- Hey, who's the Arab woman?
- [Tom] It's Lee.
- Oh, sorry.
- [John] Good night, Mr. Chan.
- Wherever you are.
- [Tom] Oh. Rollin'
away, ball away.
- He must be using
selective gas.
- Yeah.
- I guess so.
- It's all right.
Kelly, we're your only
chance out of here.
- [John] There's only one way.
- [Joel] My way or the highway.
- How?
- [John] The highwire
between the buildings.
- I couldn't.
- [John] You'll have to.
- [Tom] Hey, you
dance for strangers.
You can walk on a
tightrope for me.
- [John] Max, get the money.
- Sure thing, Mr. H.
- [Joel] Hey, they spent
20 bucks of it for a pizza.
(upbeat music)
- Is that a stuntman?
- [Tom] Are you kidding?
While they were filming this,
Lee was in his trailer
sipping a pina colada.
- No, I can't do this.
- [John] Yes, you can.
I'll help you.
- No, I can't. I can't do it.
- Take my hand.
- No.
- [Joel] I'm a
stranger in paradise.
- [John] Come on, take it.
I won't let you fall.
- Come on, take my hand!
- [Tom] I'm not
gonna take your hand!
- Take the, take my hand!
- [Tom] I'm not
gonna take your hand!
- [Joel] Take it
easy. Hey, hey, hey.
Shh.
- [Tom] Witness,
ladies and gentlemen.
- The witness sketch.
- [Joel] Ladies and gentlemen,
please direct your attention
to the highwire above.
- [Tom] That's right.
It's the Circus of
the Second-Rate Stars.
- [Kelly] Okay.
- [John] Listen to my voice.
- [Tom] Sleep!
- [John] There's
nothing below you.
There's nothing around you.
- [Tom] Water above you.
- You've got no talent,
and you can't dance.
- [John] As I step
back, you step forward.
- [Tom] We come together
'cause opposites attract.
- That's it.
- Da-da.
- [John] And you won't
fall unless I do.
- [Tom] Jinx.
- And I won't fall.
- [Joel] They're up on the wire,
half is flame, half is fire.
- [Tom] Boo! (laughing)
Tension.
- [John] Don't look down.
- I didn't.
I was so relaxed, I nodded off.
(Crow grunting)
- [John] Almost there.
- [Tom] That's Melissa Sue
Anderson, ladies and gentlemen.
Give her a hand.
(all cheering)
Let's give her a warm
round of applause.
She's done a great job.
Yay!
- [Max] Now it was my turn.
- To do another
unnecessary voice-over.
- And I'd said the chances
of tightrope walking
in San Francisco were slim.
With the Master around, you
could do it every night.
- [Tom] What are the
chances of falling?
- [Joel] Yeah, just fall.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- [Tom] Bounce it.
Don't need the rope.
- [Joel] Noonan. Noonan.
- [John] Come on, Max.
You can do it.
- [Tom] If not, can
I have your van?
- [John] Don't look down.
- You don't have a
wire cutter on you?
- [Tom] Banana peel.
- If he falls, are
we gonna have to
watch his life pass
before his eyes?
I don't think I can take it.
Dad's first "Eight
is Enough " callback.
Brother Vincent's
first tennis lesson.
Visits from Aunt Joyce
the day he realized he
was untalented enough
to star on a
primetime action show.
- Crow!
- Sorry.
- [Joel] Take it easy.
- [Tom] Really.
- [Tom] Don't hate this rope.
- [John] Almost
there. Don't lose it.
- Oh.
- Boo.
(all groaning)
- [Tom] Now they do what
they should have done
in the first place
and walk downstairs
and go out the front door.
- Master.
- Osaka, hi.
I haven't seen you since
the first episo, I mean,
that first part of the movie.
- [Okasa] They are
of no concern to me.
- [Joel] Or us.
- [Okasa] They can go.
- [Tom] But not without
these lovely parting gifts!
Tell them about it, Johnny.
- You just think
I'm going to leave--
- [John] Get her out of here.
- Uh, getting her
out of here, sir.
- [John] Go on.
- [Tom] Go on, for
crying out loud.
You're free.
You got 20 grand.
Take her out for dinner.
- [Joel] Hey, you got enough
sticks in your drawers there?
- [Tom] Hoo hoo.
Woof.
- Can you tell that I'm
sticking my tongue out at you?
(blowing raspberry)
Na-na na na-na.
- [Tom] Uh oh, I just
passed wind in my suit.
I ask you as a point of
honor, give me a second.
(suspenseful music)
With a bum, and a
chup and a chop,
and a kick and a big hiya.
(all shouting)
- A hand slice.
- [Tom] Boy, Jackie
Chan, he's not.
He's not even Charlie Chan.
- He's not even Charlie Callas.
- [Tom] He's not
even Maria Callas.
- He's not even Maria
Conchita Alonso.
- [Joel] Will you
guys stop it, please?
- Chiquita Banana with a
bung, and a boom, and a whoo!
- [Joel] Stop it. Just stop it.
- [Tom] Well, one
thing's for sure,
they both have more inner rage
than they're willing to admit.
♪ Tumble out of bed, and
stumble in the kitchen ♪
♪ Pour myself a
cup of ambition ♪
- Hey, what are
they fighting over?
The fryer exhaust at Arby's?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Looks like.
You know, these
Robert Bly weekends
are getting more
and more intense.
- [Tom] You know, last
week, I made a big mistake.
I went to a Carol Bly weekend.
- Oh, really? How?
- [Joel] I left my
liver in San Francisco.
- So these are Morris
dancers gone horribly wrong.
- [Tom] That's what I'd say.
Niagara Falls.
Slowly, I turned.
Inch by inch.
Step by step.
Closer and closer.
- And now, commence fighting!
(all shouting)
- [Joel] Yeah? Well, you
fight like a Van Patten!
- Oh, that's not
fair in a fight.
- [Joel] I just got
done fighting Shazam.
Jeepers.
- Hey, Shamir, don't
you have a kid's party
to go to or something?
- [Okasa] My friend,
time for you to die.
- [Joel] Well, that's gre, huh?
(Okasa screaming)
- "Scarecrow and
Mrs. King", in color.
- Stop that.
- Sorry.
♪ Scarecrow ♪
- Scare me.
- [Tom] Lee, you know, even
for you, that's pretty lame.
- Saved by the bell.
- [Tom] D'oh.
- PJ Trufflehoofers,
try the Phanthoozler.
- I'm a ninja warrior!
- [Tom] Oscar's back,
and he's wild as ever!
That's right.
- [Joel] You know, I love
a nice foppish dance.
- [Tom] Yeah, me too.
Yes, this is from my 1935
film, "The Prancing Ninny".
- Hey, Lee.
Tuck in the shirt,
and suck in your gut.
Or suck in your gut
and tuck in your shirt.
- [Joel] You know, Prince
stole everything from him.
- Why?
- Oh yeah.
- [Tom] Yeah, you know,
they used to call me
$3 Bill Bojangles
Robinson, as a matter of--
(all gasping)
(audience applauding)
- Hey look. Pam
Dawber's impressed.
- Oh, stupid of
power of authority.
- You think he moved great back
then, ladies and gentlemen,
we're gonna show you the
Charlie Pattersen of the '80s.
- [Joel] Hey, who
died and made him MC?
- Charlie, do a
little step for us.
- [Tom] No, not
the goose step! No!
Almost gave it away.
- Good, thank you.
Thank you very much. Great.
Great. Could you
take your seat, Dad?
Thank you.
(all cheering)
- [Tom] Give it up for
him, give it up for him.
- And Charlie, I've got a
birthday surprise for you.
- [Tom] Well, a box of Depends.
Why thank you. I didn't know.
(somber music)
- Next, on a very
special "Mrs. Ironside".
- [Tom] Aw.
♪ Time to start walking
towards your bald father ♪
- [Joel] Hey, I bought that
chair and you're gonna use it.
♪ Walking tenderly towards
Dad and falling in his arms ♪
- It's okay, Pops.
I can stand on my
own two feet now.
- Actually, dear,
you're on my two feet.
Oh, ow.
- You betcha.
(soft waltz music)
- Get me a new agent.
- [Tom] D'oh.
- [Joel] This is a warm and
tender made-for-TV moment.
(Crow sighing)
- [Tom] And there it goes.
- Let's not get carried away.
- No.
- You're the hoofer.
I'm new at this game.
- Yeah, he was also in
"The Happy Hoofer
Goes to Washington".
(Joel groaning)
- [Tom] Oh, did a
noser. (giggling)
- Come on, everybody.
Up and dance in front of her.
Puncture her balloon.
Come on.
Spoil her dreams.
(Tom humming)
- [Max] Hey, Jill.
Come on over here.
- [Tom] No more
onion rings for Lee.
Look at that gut on him.
- [Kelly] I talked to
my friend Terry today.
- [Joel] Lee can
throw his voice?
- [Kelly] She's
not your daughter.
- Well, I kind of figured a
60 year old man with glasses
wasn't my daughter.
- I'm sorry.
- [Joel] If you kiss me,
Van Patten, I'll kill you.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Oh, he's dancing
with Ziggy Stardust.
- Michael Sloan.
- [All] Shame on you.
- Indeed.
- That's for sure.
- [Tom] Well.
- Well, at least we
can enjoy another
Film Ventures International
credit sequence, huh?
- [Tom] Oh, yeah, yeah.
You know, it's what Film
Ventures International
is famous for.
Like the "Pink Panther" and
the "James Bond"
credit sequences.
- [Joel] Yeah, you know,
that was kind of weird movie.
First Demi Moore and
Claude Akins were there,
then halfway through, they
disappeared from the story.
- [Tom] Joel, when are you
going to stop living a lie?
This was not a movie.
It was a bunch of
episodes strung together.
- [Joel] Really?
- Huh.
- [Joel] You guys are cynical.
- [Tom] Oh yeah? You're cynical.
Yeah.
- [Joel] Oh, we should
get out of here, really.
- [Tom] Okay.
Well, that was fun
though, wasn't it?
- Yeah.
- At first.
- And we're going
to miss that part.
- You know, Joel, going
into this experiment,
several things were a given.
One, it had a Van Patten
in a prominent role.
Two, it was made for TV.
Three, it had a Van Patten
in a prominent role.
But I had no idea it
would be this bad.
- Yeah, really.
I mean, if you look at some
of the other 13-episode
action shows from that era,
like "Manimal", "Misfits
of Science", "Supertrain".
- Oh, I like that one.
- It was pretty good.
"Tales of the Gold Monkey".
They were all insipid,
yet clearly superior
to this piece of junk.
- Well, guys, take it easy.
The best way to beat
those made-for-TV blues
is to start your own funk
fusion TV action band, okay?
So, Crow, I want you to
start out on the drums.
Come on.
- Oh, okay.
(mimicking drum beats)
- Hey, get me.
I'm a LA studio musician.
- Come on.
- Want me to throw
a little wah-wah?
(Tom vocalizing)
- Gypsy.
(Gypsy vocalizing)
- Okay.
That sounds good.
Okay.
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
Okay, now Crow.
Put that up on
still star, will ya?
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
Okay.
"We, the officers of
the Battleship Missouri,
wish to congratulate you
on the quality programming
you are injecting in the,?
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
"Fiber optic veins
of our nation.
While in the Persian Gulf
during Operation Desert Storm,
we often felt as you must."
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
"Trapped in a steel
box with little
or no contact with
the outside world,
yet engaged in important
and dangerous work."
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
Ow.
"As comrades, we salute you.
We spent many off-duty
hours enjoying your show.
To help repay you
for the pleasure
you've given us,"
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
"We would like to do
something for you.
Some of us are engineering by
profession and would like to
offer our assistance in
designing, manufacturing,
service on,"
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
"Your torso.
Let us know if you want
any special features
such as death
lasers or detachable
radio-controlled fingers.
We eagerly await your reply."
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
What do you, what
do you think, sirs?
- Oh, oh, oh.
Very nice, Joel.
Downright funky, isn't
that right, Doctor?
- I had Jell-O today.
- I'll push the button.
(bots beatboxing)
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
♪ Rely upon the "Master
Ninja" theme song ♪
♪ 'Cause those Van Patten
brothers are so headstrong ♪
♪ "Master Ninja" theme song ♪
♪ Amen ♪
- To them, it's
some kind of ritual.